Let's fly now.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Let's try now.
Let's
fly
now.
Get
my
stage!
Let's
try
now.
Next
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Translation Check   AMS
Get
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Now!
Running into the middle of that exciting stage...
mu
ne
o
do
ru
su
tee
ji
e
ka
ke
a
ga
ru
do
ma
nna
ka
de
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Continually breakthrough your limits.
ka
gi
ri
na
ku
ri
n
ka
i
te
n
to
ppa
mi
se
te
yo
Timing       ninjacloud
We have dreams, we're fond of legends, everybody in the ring.
yu
me
ta
shi
na
mu
re
je
n
do
every
body
wa
no
na
ka
de
Don't hesitate, into the future, JUMP!
ma
yo
i
na
ku
mi
ra
i
e
no
JUMP
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
They all say they haven't fallen after they have.
o
chi
bu
re
te
na
i
to
o
chi
bu
re
te
ka
ra
i
u
ya
tsu
ba
kka
It's scary aiming at coming back from the dead but
ki
shi
ka
i
se
ne
ra
u
mi
chi
no
ri
ko
wa
ku
na
wa
i
ga
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
if the road is still blocked
ko
e
te
ku
ka
be
na
no
ni
tsu
u
ka
te
n
na
no
ni
Karaokes      KmE
after I've crossed all the barriers,
fu
sa
i
de
ru
na
ra
I need to realize I'm not alone.
hi
to
ri
ja
na
i
ji
ka
ku
o
Slam it!
t
o
d
k
e
We have to set the rim on fire!
w
e
h
a
v
e
t
o
m
a
k
e
a
R
I
M
F
I
R
E
Let's combine our power and our minds.
a
w
s
e
r
o
p
w
e
r
n
o
a
k
n
o
m
i
n
d
Encoding      Your Mom
We don't need any excuses.
i
w
a
k
e
i
r
a
n
z
o
Gotta dream, exceed your limits, and war.
G
o
t
a
d
r
e
a
m
g
e
n
k
a
i
t
o
w
a
r
I need to face up to my common sense,
ta
chi
ha
da
ka
ru
no
wa
ri
ka
i
shi
su
gi
ta
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
joushiki to
which I know all too well,
kodoku no maibotsu
and bury my loneliness.
RIM
FIRE!!
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
Impossible...
（火神(かがみ)）まさか…
It's probably exactly what you're thinking.
（黒子(くろこ)）たぶん その まさかです
Kise is trying to copy Aomine's style.
黄瀬(きせ)君がやろうとしていることは
青峰(あおみね)君のスタイルのコピーです
Don't drag your feet, Kise.
（青峰）
タラタラしてんじゃねーよ 黄瀬
I'm not patient enough to wait until you're ready.
テメエの準備が整うまで
おとなしく待ってやるほど—
オレの気は長くねーぞ
Kise finally...
（日向(ひゅうが)）ついに 黄瀬が…
broke past...
（伊月(いづき)）エースの青峰を…
their ace, Aomine!
（小金井(こがねい)）抜いたあ！
調子に乗ってんじゃねぇぞ
黄瀬ぇ！
Don't get ahead of yourself, Kise!
No!
（さつき）ダメーっ！
Episode 25
My and Your Basketball
（原澤(はらさわ)）うん
The fourth quarter's going to be really tough with Aomine having already picked up his fourth foul.
第４クオーターまるまる残して—
青峰君の４ファウルは
正直 厳しい
とはいえ １分でも長く コートには
いてもらわないといけません
But we still need you to be on the court as long as possible.
フォーメーションを少し変えて
オフェンスとディフェンス共に…
Change your formation a little and work together on offense and defense—
The little stuff doesn't matter.
（青峰）細けーことは いい
最終クオーター
ボールは 全部 オレに よこせ
Just give me the ball every time down in the last quarter.
I'll crush them.
たたき潰してやる
Hey!
（さつき）ちょっと…
（若松(わかまつ)）テメー！
You bastard!
（若松）マジ
自己中も たいがいにしろよ！
Seriously, keep your ego in check!
Let him do what he wants.
（今吉(いまよし)）好きに やらせえ
キャプテン…
Captain!
We can handle the rest of the team,
他のチームなら まだしも—
今の黄瀬君の相手をできるのは
青峰しかおらん
but the only one who can take on Kise in his current state is Aomine.
Whether we take him off or he's kicked off the court...
ひっこめようが退場しようが—
おらんくなった時点で
ゲームオーバーや
Once he's gone, it's game over.
It doesn't matter if you try to handle it or get all emotional.
ケツ持とうとして
ヘソ曲げられてもかなわん
The only thing we can do is prepare ourselves for the worst.
なら もう 腹くくるしかないやろ
If victorious, we're heroes.
勝てば官軍 負ければ賊軍
とどのつまり そんだけの話や
If defeated, we're losers.
Either way, that's the story.
（黄瀬）
ハァ ハァ ハァ… フゥー…
Are you okay?
（森山(もりやま)）大丈夫か？
（黄瀬）まあ なんとか
Yeah, I'm all right.
仮に 青峰が退場したとしても—
Even if Aomine gets kicked off the court,
we still need you to catch up.
追いつくには
やっぱ オマエが必要だ
最後まで立っててくれねーと
困るぜ
If you aren't standing until the end,
we'll be in trouble.
No problem.
余裕っス 信じてもらえねーかも
しれないっスけど—
You may not believe me,
オフでも
欠かさず走ってきたんスよ？
but I even ran on our days off.
I know, you mor-moro...
（早川(はやかわ)）知ってぅわ！
この バぇ！ バッ… バぇやおー…
かむなよ…
Don't stutter.
You're always doing that kind of stuff!
大体 オマエは
いつも いつも そうやって…
I believe in you.
（森山）信じてるさ とっくに…
I always have.
You're silly...
（笠松）甘っ…
The fourth quarter will now begin.
（アナウンス）
第４クオーターを開始します
Touou hasn't changed their lineup.
（日向）
桐皇(とうおう)はメンバーチェンジしないな
Anyone would lose their edge with four fouls.
（伊月）けど どんなヤツでも
４ファウルなら 動きは にぶる
Are they going to be okay?
大丈夫か？
There it is!
（小金井）来たぁ！
They scored already!
（土田(つちだ)）いきなり １本…
Not only has he not changed with four fouls,
（笠松）４ファウルで
変わらないどころか—
すごみ増してやがる
なんて集中力！
but he's even more amazing.
What incredible focus.
He really is a monster.
（武内(たけうち)）やはり 化け物か
“キセキの世代”エース 青峰大輝(だいき)
The ace of the Generation of Miracles, Aomine Daiki.
What?
That was exactly the same shot.
（ホイッスル）
（火神）まったく 同じ！？
They're exactly the same!
（観客１）まったく同じだぁー
（観客２）
どちらも 一歩も引かない…
Neither one's backing down!
This isn't just a fistfight. It's an all-out brawl!
殴り合いっつーより
もはや 取っ組み合いだろ！？ これ
I knew this would happen.
（今吉）
やっぱ こうなってしもたか
にしても つくづく
恐ろしいもんやで“キセキの世代”
The Generation of Miracles are truly terrifying.
Kise!
（青峰）黄瀬ぇ！
（黄瀬）青峰っち！
Aominecchi!
It went in!
（観客）入ったぁー！
Kaijo
Touou
I can't let my guard down for a second.
（黄瀬）一瞬も気が抜けない
頭 痛くなりそうっスわ…
I feel like I'm getting a headache.
That must be tough.
（リコ）しんどいわね…
I'm exhausted.
ほんと 疲れた〜
Not you!
アンタじゃなくて！
I've never seen such static flow in a game before.
ここまで流れが変わらない試合は
初めてだわ
中の選手は
相当 精神 削られてるはずよ
The players on the blocks must really be wearing down mentally.
It's especially tough on Kaijo.
特に キツイのは 追う海常(かいじょう)だ
They've been stuck at eight to ten points behind forever,
長時間
８点差と10点差を繰り返し—
but even with the clock ticking, they still haven't given up.
差が縮まらないまま
時間が どんどん なくなっていく
（今吉）緊張の糸は
いつ切れても おかしくない
They should be snapping any time now.
I'll never give up!
（笠松）諦めるか…
チャンスは 必ず来る！
We'll definitely get our chance!
We can't just roll over when he's trying so hard!
あいつが踏んばってるのに
簡単に へこたれっか！
I'll admit he's good, but I won't let my guard down until it's over.
（青峰）認めてやる… どころか
最後まで気は抜かねーよ
As long as he has those eyes, there's no telling what will happen.
その目をしてるかぎりは
何が起こるか 分かんねぇ
As long as he has the same eyes as Tetsu!
テツと同じ目をしてるかぎり
（若松）ったく
頭が真っ白になってきやがる
My head is starting to go blank.
Those two are working hard too,
あいつら２人も よくやるが
こっちも ほとんど—
but I feel like I've been doing nothing but sprinting back and forth, damn it.
ひたすら 往復ダッシュ
してるよーなもんだ クソ！
Sakurai!
（諏佐(すさ)）桜井(さくらい)！
（桜井）え？
The balance is broken!
均衡が崩れた
海常のチャンスだ！
This is Kaijo's chance!
Stop them! Defend at all costs!
止めろ！ ここは死守だ！
One minute left.
Kaijo
Touou
（木吉(きよし)）残り１分
（木吉）
ここで勝負が決まる！
This is where the game will be decided.
これを決めれば 差は スリー２本分
チームも一気に士気を取り戻せる
If they make this shot, they'll only be two threes behind.
It'll boost the team's morale.
If they miss, they'll have reached their time limit.
逆に 落とせば タイムリミットだ
つまり…
In other words, practically speaking...
事実上…
It's their last chance!
最後の一騎打ちだ！
（青峰）どう来る 右か 左か…
Where will he come from?
From the right or from the left?
If I were in his position,
もし オレが逆の立場なら
左フェイクからクロスオーバーで…
I would fake to the left and crossover...
To the right!
（黄瀬）
右！ だから ウラをかいて—
So I'll outsmart him by doing the opposite and go...
そこから もう１つ…
Left... But what if he tries to outsmart me again?
（青峰）
左！ のウラをかかれたら？
Right or left?
（火神）右か！？ 左か！？
Since we both know the other so well, there's no point in trying to read each other.
（青峰）手の内を
お互い 知りつくしてる以上—
読み合いなんざ 無意味
A formless shot?
いきなりフォームレスシュート！？
He's fast. He's going to stop him!
（森山）
速いっ… これは止められる！
何！？
What?
Kasamatsu!
（今吉）笠松！？
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
止めたぁ！？
He stopped them?
They lost their only chance.
千載一遇のチャンスを逃したな
No one can react fast enough to do that.
（若松）あのタイミングで後出しで
反応できるヤツなんていねぇ
Did he know what he was going to do?
読んでたのか！？ けど…
But...
How?
（黄瀬）なんで！？
You've done pretty well up until now, but in the very end, you finally made a mistake.
（青峰）ここまで よくやったが
最後の最後に ヘマしたな
If it had been a one-on-one, you may have had a chance to win.
あのままワンオンワンだったら—
オマエにも
勝つ可能性はあったかもしれねえ
You faked by looking one way and...
あのとき オマエは
目線のフェイクを １つ入れた
looked at Kasamatsu on your right.
と同時に
右サイドの笠松を見た
In that position, I wouldn't fake with my eyes.
が オレなら あの場面で
目線のフェイクは しねえ
At first glance, a pass seems like the most surprising move,
つまり パスは
一見 意表をついた選択だが—
but it's also something I would never do and is the easiest thing to predict.
逆に言えば オレの動きにない
一番 予測されやすい選択だ
My style of basketball isn't designed to rely on my teammates.
オレのバスケは
仲間を頼るようにはできてねぇ
I missed my only chance.
（黄瀬）唯一のチャンスを逃した
この試合は もう…
This game is...
Get ready for the next play!
（笠松）切りかえろ！
試合は まだ終わっちゃいねーぞ！
This game's not over yet!
Kaijo
（青峰）オレの勝ちだ 黄瀬
I win, Kise.
らしくないことしたせいで
あっけない幕切れだったな
Because you tried to do something out of character, this game came to a disappointing end.
Ultimately, you lost because you were weak and relied on your teammates...
結局 敗因は—
最後の最後にチームメートに頼った
オマエの弱さだ
in the very end.
そうかも… しんないっスね
You might be right.
But I couldn't have made it this far by myself.
（黄瀬）けど オレだけじゃ
ここまで やれなかった
（黄瀬）ぬうっ
I don't mind if we lose,
だから
負けるだけなら まだしも—
but I can't be the only one to give up!
オレだけ諦めるわけには
いかねーんスわ
If there's any reason I lost,
敗因があるとしたら ただ…
まだ力が足りなかっただけっス
it's simply because I wasn't strong enough yet!
フン…
当たり前なこと言ってんじゃねーよ
Don't state the obvious.
Kaijo
Touou
（審判）試合 終了ー！
Game over!
Both teams, line up!
（審判）両チーム 整列！
（森山）完全に足に来てる
He's feeling it in his legs.
Does copying the Generation of Miracles put exceptional strain on him?
“キセキの世代”のコピーは
並外れた負担がかかるのか！？
（黄瀬）ええぃ！
Can you stand?
立てるか？ もう少しだけ 頑張れ
Hang in there a little longer.
先輩… オレ…
Senpai, I...
You did well.
（笠松）オマエは よく やったよ
Besides, it's not all over yet.
それに これで
すべて終わったわけじゃない
You can pay him back this winter.
借りは 冬 返せ
ええんか？ なんも言わんで
元チームメートやろ？
Are you sure you don't need to say anything?
Isn't he your former teammate?
What?
は？ いくらアンタでも
あんまチャカすと キレんぞ？
I'll even get pissed at you if you make fun of me.
勝者が敗者にかける言葉なんざ
ねえよ
There's nothing for a winner to say to a loser.
98 to 110, Touou Academy wins!
（審判）98対110で
桐皇学園高校の勝ち！ 礼！
Bow!
Thank you very much!
（選手たち）
ありがとうございました！
Quit moping!
しょぼくれてんじゃねえ！
全員が すべてを出し切った！
We all gave everything we had!
全国ベスト８だろう！
胸張って帰るぞ！
We're still in the country's top eight!
Let's go home with our heads held high!
Touou Academy
Dressing Room
All, right! We won the Inter-High quarter—
よっしゃー！ インターハイ
準々決勝！ 勝利を祝って か…
毎度 それ やらんと あかんか？
Do you have to do that every time?
Huh? Where's Aomine?
あれ？ 青峰さんは？
He already left.
（諏佐）もう帰ったぞ
ええっ！ 早っ
What? That was quick.
いや でも
今回 結構ヤバかったっスよ！
That game was really close!
Why aren't you guys more excited?
むしろ なんで いつもと
テンション変わんねえんスか！？
I guess I was nervous,
確かに まあ ヒヤヒヤしたわ
but we won despite everything that happened in the end.
ただ結局
どう転んでも ウチが勝ったしな
（若松）あのバカだって—
Even that idiot gave it everything he had!
いっぱいいっぱい
だったじゃないスか！
I see. You guys don't know.
（今吉）そっか…
オマエらは知らんかったな
青峰は まだ 底は見せてへん
Aomine still hasn't shown us everything he can do.
（今吉）前に 一度だけ
見せてもろたんや
He showed me once before.
あいつには
もう１つ上がある
He has an even higher level.
Well, he can't do it all the time.
まあ いうても
あれは いつでもは できん
What he didn't do this time, he probably couldn't do.
今回は やらんかった半分
できんかった半分ってとこやろ
If there's anything to worry about with him,
強いて 心底 心配したとすれば…
あいつの中に残っとった甘さ…
ってとこやな
I'd say it's the soft spot he still has.
（黄瀬）あれ？
そういえば 笠松先輩は？
Huh? Where's Kasamatsu-senpai?
（森山）
ん… ああ 先 行ってろとさ
He told us to go on ahead.
I'll go check on him.
オレ 様子 見てくるっスよ
なあ いいから やめとけ
Don't bother.
He's right.
（黄瀬）
そうだ… 今は 戻っちゃダメだ
I can't go back now.
（黄瀬）そんなヒマあったら 進め
一歩でも前へ
If I have time for that,
I should move forward... even if it's only one step.
It's been reaffirmed.
（火神）再確認したぜ
これが“キセキの世代”
This is the Generation of Miracles.
We'll play against these guys again this winter.
（伊月）
冬に また こんなヤツらと…
（土田）勝てるのか？
Can we beat them?
No, we will win.
（日向）いや… 勝つ！
That said, the difference between us is still too great.
（木吉）
とはいえ まだ差がありすぎる
We'll have to get stronger.
今より
もっと強くならんといかんな
We can't keep brooding forever!
いつまでも呆(ほう)けてらんないわ！
帰って 早く練習するわよ！
Let's go home and start practicing right away!
What? We're leaving?
え？ 帰んの！？
この大会 他の
“キセキの世代”も出てるんじゃ
Aren't there more members of the Generation of Miracles playing in this tournament?
そりゃあ
できれば 最後まで見たいわよ！
I wish we could watch until the end!
We can find a hotel, and...
（火神）
いや だから ホテルとか見っけて…
A hotel, huh? Hey, Kagami.
ホテルか… おい 火神
どこに そんな金 あんだ！
Where do you have the money for that?
Are you a rich kid?
ボンボンか！？ オマエ
実は ちょっとボンボンか！？
（火神）いででで！
いだい！ いだいって！
Are you actually some rich kid?
You did say you live by yourself!
一人暮らしのくせして
大体 そんな何泊も増やしたら—
Besides, if we extend our trip too much, the coach's dad will kill us!
カントクの親父さんに
ぶっ殺されんだよ！
Winter will be here before you know it!
冬なんて あっという間だ！
帰って 練習あるのみ！
We'll go home and practice!
Yeah!
（一同）お… おお！
（テツヤ２号(にごう)）わん！
Number Two, quiet.
（黒子）２号 シーッ！
（テツヤ２号）わん！
Wasn't it an amazing game, Shin?
（高尾(たかお)）
すげえ試合だったな 真(しん)ちゃん
（緑間(みどりま)）
な… なぜ 分かったのだよ！？
How did you know?
I knew there was no way you wouldn't come.
来ないわけないと思ってさ
つうか いいかげん
それで変装した気になるの—
Anyway, you should really stop thinking you've managed to disguise yourself like that.
やめたほうがいいと思うけど
It's none of your business.
（緑間）大きな お世話なのだよ
Kise and Aomine really are monsters.
やっぱ バケモンだな 黄瀬も青峰も
Don't tell me what I already know.
分かりきったことを言うな
Besides, there is a monster standing right before your eyes too.
それに化け物は
オマエの目の前にもいるのだよ
冬が楽しみだな
This winter should be fun.
もう出してあげても
大丈夫じゃない？
You can probably let him out now.
You're right.
（黒子）そうですね
Huh? I feel like I've been here before.
（紫原(むらさきばら)）アーララ〜？
なんか 前 ここ 通ったような…
Where am I?
どこだ ここ？
（火神）でけえな
ジャージ着てるってことは選手か？
He's huge.
If he's wearing a jersey, he must be a player.
He must be at least two meters tall.
２メートルは あるか
I mean, I don't want to play basketball anyway.
ていうかあー やだやだ バスケとか
疲れるし…
It's so tiring.
Oh, wow. This new flavor's pretty good.
って アララ…
この新味は いいぞう
What are you doing?
（日向）おい 何してんだ？
置いてくぞー！
We'll leave you behind!
What's wrong?
どうした？
Nothing.
いえ…
ちょっと
あいさつし損ねただけです
I just forgot to greet someone.
（日向）
よし！ 全員 そろってるな？
All right! Everyone's here, right?
Um...
（河原）あの…
（日向）はい 黒子君ですね
Yes, it's Kuroko, isn't it?
No, actually...
（河原）いえ！ それが…
You still suck at everything besides passing.
（火神）相変わらず
パス以外は からっきしだな
How did you know I was here?
どうして
ここだと 分かったんです？
I thought watching the game might have gotten your blood pumping.
あんな試合 見せられて 頭に
血が上ったんじゃねえかと思ってよ
つい 熱くなりました
I am heated up.
If you're heated up, I'm practically boiling.
オマエで熱くなるなら
オレは沸騰しそうだぜ
彼らのプレーには
人をそうさせる力があるんです
Their play has the power to do that to people.
昔から
It's always been that way.
（火神）なあ
Hey.
What are the rest of the Generation of Miracles like?
“キセキの世代”の残りの連中って
どんなヤツらなんだ？
I only know what they were like in middle school.
ボクが知っているのは あくまでも
中学時代の彼らでしかありません
黄瀬君や緑間君や青峰君が
格段の進歩を遂げたように—
Kise,
Midorima,
and Aomine have all made significant improvements.
I'm sure the other two have done the same.
残りの２人も成長しているはずです
紫原君も…
Murasakibara...
赤司(あかし)君も…
and Akashi...
Murasakibara... Akashi...
（火神）紫原… 赤司…
Not even I can imagine what they are like now.
今 現在の彼らが
どうなっているのか—
ボクにも想像がつきません
Honnouteki naru situation
An instinctive situation,
tatakau imi o sagasu kono imitation
searching for a reason to fight this imitation.
Kurayami kara koboreru raito
Use the light that seeps from the darkness,
torawareta yourself kowase
and break free from your imprisonment.
Jiyuu ukeirete wa mogaite kuratte fuantei
Accept your freedom and struggle through your insecurities.
Kodou ga boku o tsukiage spy kidottenda
The pulsation throws me for a loop and I begin to spy.
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best"
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best."
And Rhythm like this never ends
And Rhythm like this never ends.
Sometimes your voice reached to me
Sometimes your voice reached to me,
Because I don't want to face the fate
because I dont want to face the fate.
Tobi tachitaku naru tte?
You say you wanna jump back up?
Katarurizumu oboete ndarou
You remember the catal rhythm, don't you?
Mune ni hibiku akirame no kako e
To the past resounding resignation in your chest,
Sabita sukoaboodo mitai ni
like a rusty scoreboard,
kimi mo koko de furuete ndarou?
you're shaking, aren't you?
Toriaezu wa mayoi no nai mirai e
For now, confidently head into the future.
Zanzou demo ii nda
Even if it's just a fragment of yourself.
Future aspect
（火神）１人残らず ぶっ倒す
I'll crush them all.
見せてやろうぜ オレたちの…
いや オレとオマエのバスケをよ
Let's show them. Our...
No, my and your basketball.
はい
Yes.
冬は戦争だ
This winter will be war!